

George GIS Manager

United Kingdon | Local Government

Previous GIS Specialist, GIS Analyst, Information Systems Officer

Education University of Leeds

213

Background



I apply 20 years of experience in GeoSpatial to the planning and deployment of enterprise scale Spatial Data Infrastructure. I lead in all aspects of system implementation from the development of GIS strategies and business cases through to configuration, training and sign-off.

I believe in LI for the masses. My mission is to expand and improve the use of LI within my organization. I provide an increasing number of customers with the tools and data they need to successfully include location in their analyses.

As the reach of LI increases, so do my challenges:

Ensure Data Quality and Integrity - so all of my customers use the latest-greatest data I can provide to drive decisions

Exercise Control Over Spatial Data Creation and Maintenance - I can't ensure data integrity without doing this

Simplify and Scale - I can no longer think of one-off projects, too many silos to



Experience

GIS Manager UK Local Government - Council Office July 2010 - Present (5 Years 1 Months)

Duties and Responsibilities:

- · Strategic management of the enterprise GIS & Customer Data Infrastructure
- The design, development, implementation and governance of technical tools relating to Geographical Information Systems (GIS) and customer database
- · Leading on the development of the corporate Customer Information Management Strategy and the corporate Geographical Information Management Strategy
- · Establishment of governance mechanisms to ensure accuracy of data and integration with other core & service ICT applications
- Engage stakeholders & user groups to maintain awareness of business needs & deliver training programs
- Create development roadmaps with regards to the Enterprise GIS, LLPG & Customer Database solutions in order to support the strategic objectives of the Council and strategic partners
- Manage system contracts and vendor relationships
- · GIS Budget Management

GIS Analyst UK Local Governement - council office January 2000 - June 2010 (10 Years 6 Months)

GIS / CAD Guy Public Sector job - field data collection

January 1995 - January 2000 (5 Years 1 Months)



University of Leeds
BS or Masters, Geography / Cartography / IT Systems





23 Strategy

21 MapInfo

19 ESRI

17 Data Quality

15 People Management



People Also Viewed

Leanne W

Spatial Data Administrator QLD Government



Andrew D

Customer and GeoInformation Analyst - Barnsley Council



Natalie F

GIS Manager EPCOR Water Services



Donna E GIS Officer

Torfaen Council



Craig W

Head of Information Systems Sedgemoor Council



Michael D

GIS Systems Manager Southern Water - Brighton UK